I'm sure if you review what has happened to you this year
It's going to be probably a very busy day for you
Very busy year for you
我相信今天來到聖誕主日的時候
再看看過去一年發生的事
在你的生命當中可能是非常忙和非常困難
Perhaps this year has been a very very tough year for you
可能對你來說今年真是富有挑戰
For many of us at UV, it has been a challenging year
We have families dealing with sickness, dealing with death and crisis and difficulties
And our ministries are also tackling with different challenges
And in general, I think there are so many stresses in our life
在我們這個UV family裏面
有很多的大英姊妹都在生命裏面
Deal with很多困難,很多的挑戰
在我們事工裏面其實都是一樣
我們都遇見很多不同的困難
我想大致上,你想一想今年發生的事
都應該是幾緊張今年
以及是幾多事情
So I pray that the songs that we offer to you
The songs that we are going to sing
The Christmas songs, the baptism testimony
The candle lighting ceremony that we are going to do later
Will all remind you the real meaning of Christmas
雖然我們生命裏面很忙
但我相信今天我們這個崇拜裏面
我們所唱的詩歌,我們默想的內容
以及看見L的水禮的見證等等
甚至我們等下結束的時候
最後的時候,我們會有一個燃點燭光的儀式
我希望這些所有的細節都會提醒你
到底聖誕節真正的意義是甚麼
Let me read this passage on screen
It is taken from the Bible, the Gospel of Luke
From chapter 2
讓我讀讀在螢幕上
路加福音這段聖經
Here the angelic choir is announcing the good news
The good news of the birth of our Saviour
To the shepherds in the field in Bethlehem
The very good news of the birth of our Saviour Jesus Christ
這段聖經就是天使天君
好像一個合唱團一樣
在天上去唱歌,去讚美神
以及去報告一個大好的訊息
就是向野地上的伯利恆的牧羊人
向他們說,我們的救主耶穌基督
是今天出生的
Suddenly the angel was joined by the vast host of other angels
the armies of heaven
They praised God and said
Glory to God in highest heaven
Peace on earth to those with whom God is pleased
忽然有一大隊的天兵和那天使
去讚美上帝說
在至高之處,榮耀歸於上帝
在地上平安歸於他所起乙的近
Now one of the Christmas traditions
many Americans would do is to watch some movie, some Christmas movie
在美國裡面,有些人,不同的家庭
有一個聖誕的傳統
就是大家坐在一起,在家裡看一些舊的電影
舊的聖誕的電影
And I don't know if you do that or not
我不知道你會不會這樣做
But many of the families, American families
will be watching Charlie Brown Christmas this season
有很多美國的家庭,他們懷舊的時候
就會看這個叫做 Charlie Brown Christmas
聖誕節的影片,這個電影
How many of you have watched this before?
Charlie Brown Christmas, raise your hand
Only a handful, okay, only a handful
有誰沒看過?
沒看過,回去看一下
So in this movie, Charlie Brown, the main character
is doing his best to organize a Christmas play with the kids
這個電影主要講到一個情節
就是Charlie Brown這個主角
想和學生和同學一起去搞一個聖誕節的話劇
做一些牧羊人等等
But as you can tell
Charlie Brown is trying to organize this play with other kids
and kids are not listening to you, right?
They run around and no one in the story
is listening to Charlie Brown
and everyone starts to criticize Charlie Brown
for his lack of organization or lack of leadership
Charlie was very frustrated and nobody
understands the real meaning of Christmas
So at the end, Charlie Brown almost gave up
Charlie Brown就去和其他的同學
一起搞一個聖誕的話劇
誰知道搞不成
因為很多小孩很頑皮
小孩不會聽你的
And by the way, we have some kids joining us today
which is great, right?
They are noisy, they are running around
they are joyful and they want to express themselves
So as the story goes
Charlie Brown was very frustrated
Charlie Brown搞不成的時候
他就很辛苦和很沮喪
因為沒有人明白這個聖誕節真正的意思是怎樣
所以他最後就差不多想放棄
However, at the end, as the story goes
With all the chaos with the kids
Charlie Brown has a very wise friend
called Ninus
So Ninus stepped in
and Ninus has always been a timid, shy
and, you know, less than confident character
a less than confident kid in the story
但是最後,Charlie Brown有一個好朋友
叫Ninus, Ninus就是一個很害羞
和沒什麼自信的小孩
And that's why whenever you see Ninus
in Charlie Brown stories or movies
Ninus always has a security blanket in his hand
Okay? Ring the bell?
Remind of this character?
Always has a security blanket in his hand
But Ninus volunteer himself
to tell the story of the Bible
and the true meaning of Christmas under the spotlight
那麼這個好朋友
Ninus雖然是一個很害羞的小孩
但是他經常有一塊布拿著
那塊毛巾
英文叫做security blanket
就是那種安全感給他
所以這個很害羞的小孩
就是一個Charlie Brown的好朋友
那麼他最後就和Charlie Brown說
不要緊,我去告訴你
聖誕節是真正的meaning
真正的意義是什麼
所以他就走了去台上
他就去到講出這個聖誕的故事
和聖誕的真正的意思
Do you want to watch this movie?
你想不想看這部電影?
Okay, I'll let you watch 2 minutes
我今天剪輯了兩分鐘給你
有字幕在上面
Okay, so we're going to watch 2 minutes
of the most spectacular moment
in this entire movie
那麼我們想看一看這個電影
其中兩分鐘最重要最精彩的那部份
好嗎?
I guess you were right, Linus
I shouldn't have picked this little tree
Everything I do turns into a disaster
I guess I really don't know
what Christmas is all about
Isn't there anyone
who knows what Christmas is all about?
Sure, Charlie Brown
I can tell you what Christmas is all about
Lights, please
And there were in the same country shepherds
Abiding in the field
Keeping watch over their flock by night
And lo, the angel of the Lord came upon them
And the glory of the Lord showed round about them
And they were sore afraid
And the angel said unto them, Fear not
For behold, I bring you tidings of great joy
Which shall be to all people
For unto you is born this day in the city of David
A Savior, which is Christ the Lord
And this shall be a sign unto you
You shall find the babe wrapped
In swaddling clothes lying in a manger
And suddenly there was with the angel
A multitude of the heavenly host
Praising God and saying
Glory to God in the highest
And on earth peace, good will toward men
And that is what Christmas is all about
Charlie Brown
Do you enjoy the movie?
Two minutes
Is it good?
Now, I want to tell you guys
There is one little detail
One little detail in this clip
Most of the people missed
In this two-minute video
Many people didn't pay attention to a detail
And that one little detail is that
Right in the middle of Niners
Telling the story of Christmas from the Bible
And telling other people
The real meaning of Christmas
A child is born
You see Niners actually
Drop his security blanket
有個細節大家冇留意
就是Niners好怕醜
但佢講呢個聖誕故事嘅時候
其實佢就係將佢嗰個安全嘅布
係掉低
大家冇留意
Now, I'm sure we all have our security blanket
我相信我哋個個都有嗰塊安全布
Things that give you peace
Things that give you security
Things that give you confidence
嗰塊安全布可以代表
有一啲嘅嘢係畀我哋平安
畀我哋安穩
畀我哋有自信
畀我哋有信心
May be our bank account
The money that we have
Our friends
Our career
Our identity
Or some sort of certainty in our future
可能係代表住
可能我哋銀行裏面有幾多錢
我哋囤積咗幾多嘢
我哋嘅朋友
有冇人接受我哋
我哋嘅職業
我哋嘅工作
我哋嘅前景
我哋嘅將來
我哋嘅身份
呢啲都可能係我哋嘅安全布
And we all try to grab that thing
Or some things
That will give us everlasting peace
To give us a little bit more peace
A little bit more confidence
But as you know
In reality
Those things do not last
They often disappoint us
We always want to grab those things
Grab those things
Think those things are for us
Eternal safety
Eternal peace
We always hold on to it
But we know
In reality
Many times
These things make us disappointed
May be health
May be our well-being
May be our future
Our security
Whatever that is
Your security blanket
The safety blanket that I have
可能係我嘅健康
可能我自己嘅生命裏面
任何嘅嘢我都拿得住嘅
我哋總係覺得
嗰啲嘢可以俾到我哋
永久嘅平安
And I want to tell you
They often disappoint us
Nothing can be guaranteed
呢啲嘢成日會令到我哋
生命裏面好沮喪
好失望
Now what Christmas is all about
Is a different kind of peace
It's a true everlasting peace
It's peace with God our Father
聖誕就係話畀我聽
有另外一種嘅平安
呢種平安係一種永遠嘅平安
呢種嘅平安係同我哋
創造主
天父之間有嘅平安
Peace in times of chaos
Peace in times of difficulty
Peace in times of challenge
Knowing that God is with us
God is always with us
In Jesus Christ
喺危機裏面我哋仍然有平安
喺困難裏面我哋仍然有盼望
有平安
就係因為我哋同上帝認識
因為上帝喺難處
喺挑戰裏面
仍然同我哋同行
And that is the everlasting peace
呢個就係永遠嘅平安
呢個就係聖誕嘅意思
The real meaning of Christmas
Glory to God in highest heaven
And peace on earth
To those with whom God is pleased
在至高之處榮耀歸於神
在地上平安歸於他所棄於敵人
And the people that God is pleased with
are those who have put their faith
in Christ Jesus
所有上帝所喜悅嘅人
就係果啲願意行出一步
將佢信心擺喺耶穌基督身上嘅人
So how can we receive the gift of God
in Christ Jesus
我哋點樣能夠喺上帝嗰度
攞到呢個真正嘅平安
The first thing we have to do
Is to let go
If you want to receive a gift
You have to receive it with open hands
But if we are holding on to our security blankets
Our stuff
You know our hands are not open
And our hearts are not open
Then we cannot receive the gift of God
How can we receive the gift of God
If our hands are not open
And our hearts are not open
How can we receive it
Because what we hold on to is our security blankets
What we hold on to is our stuff
If we hold on to it
We think it can give us peace
But it cannot
If you want to receive the gift of God
You have to let go
And open your hands and hearts
Then you can receive the real peace
The real gift
So how can you receive the gift of God
Only by your hands
Not holding on to your security blankets
How can you receive the gift of God
Only by letting go of your security blankets
Then you can open your hands
To receive the Christmas gift from God
That is Jesus Christ
How can we experience the gift of God
If our hearts are filled with overwhelm
With our stuff and our idols
Our work, our overwhelmingly busy schedule
We etch out God in our life
The only way we can receive the gift of God
Is that we let go of this stuff
And with an open heart we come to God
And say thank you for giving me
The very son of yours
如何能夠拿到上帝給我們最好
聖誕的禮物
我們先放手
打開我們的心
才能夠拿到上帝給我們
一個最好最好的禮物
So at the end I want to invite you
All of you to take this moment
Take this very moment
To reconnect
To reconnect with God
God who created you
God who loves you
God who is always with you
So at the end I want to welcome you
To invite you
To use this moment
To reconnect with God
God who created you
God who loves you
So at the end I want to welcome you
To reconnect with God
To use this moment
So at the end I want to welcome you
To reconnect with God
Let me read this prayer first
Before we recite it together
So I want to invite you to recite it
With your words or with your heart
我想讀讀這個祈禱
然後我們才用這個祈禱
去討論好嗎
你可以開口和我一起祈禱
也可以在心裡和我一起祈禱
去接受耶穌基督這位最好最好的
聖誕節的最好的禮物
Dear Lord Jesus
The prayer says
I ask you to grant me peace
Peace in my heart
When it feels like the world all around us
Spins out of control
Help me stay focused on you
The Son of God, born in humble manger
I come to you, God, with an open heart
I know my need for your grace
And your forgiveness
I ask you to be my Savior and my Lord
Cleanse me from my sins
And make me new today
Fill me with your peace
And guide me in your way
In Jesus' name
親愛的主耶穌
這個祈禱這麼說
求你賜給我平安
在我心裡面賜給我平安
特別當世界失控的時候
讓我專注在你身上
就是誕生在卑微馬槽的神的耳前
我謙卑的來到你面前
知道我需要你的恩典
需要你的赦免
我求你今天成為我救主生命的主
去潔淨我的罪
更新我
讓你的平安充滿我
引導我走你的道路
奉主耶穌的名字
我們一起來用這個祈禱
去結束,好嗎?
然後我們會有一個燭光禮
我們會通過我們的燭光
去給每一個人
我們要結束今天的祈禱
在燈光祭禱中
我們會通過燈光
到燈光
但我們要結束這個祈禱
好嗎?
我們先用英文去做
如果你想加入我
請做
但你也可以在心中祈禱
我們來做
親愛的主耶穌
我求你賜給我平安
平安在我心裡
當世界失控的時候
讓我專注在你身上
神的兒子,生在謙遜中
我來給你謙遜的心
我知道我需要你的寬恕
我求你為我的救護者
清除我的罪惡
讓我變得更新
充滿我和你的平安
引導我走你的道路
奉主耶穌的名字
Amen
親愛的主耶穌
我求你賜給我平安
在我心中賜給我平安
特別當世界失控的時候
讓我專注在你身上
就是誕生在
卑微馬槽的神的兒子
我謙卑的來到你面前
知道我需要你的恩典和赦免
我求你今天成為我的救主
生命的主
潔淨我罪,更新我
讓你的平安充滿我
引導我走在你的道路上
奉主耶穌的名求
Amen
我們一起祈禱
主耶穌,這是我們的禱告
Lord Jesus,這就是我們的祈禱
我們的祈禱是為了給你空間
我們的祈禱就是
希望在生命中能夠有空間給你
我們邀請耶穌進入我們的生命中
再次成為我們的救主
再次成為我們的主
So cleanse us and renew us
and guide us in your way
in Jesus' name
上帝,我們求你今天成為我們的救主
生命的主
潔淨我們,更新我們
引導我們走前面的道路
奉主耶穌的名自己救
Amen